clone - git clone, copies a remote repository into your current directory
init - git init, creates a new empty repo in your current directory
add - git add, add file to cwd
commit - git commit, commit file to stagin area
status - git status, lists changes in working directory, and staged files
push - git push (no argument), push file to repository
log - git log, prints commit history of repo
push - git push, incorporates changes from local repo into origin
